San Francisco Bay Area, CA; Ph: 312-330-8641

amita.ekbote@gmail.com

Summary

Distributed systems engineer with 10 years experience working on platform teams. Self driven and passionate about delivering value to customers, worked with internal and external customers at Amazon and Netflix. Experienced with leading adoption for new platforms.

Skills

Golang, Java, Python, AWS, Docker, Kubernetes, CI/CD tools.

Work Experience

NETFLIX, Los Gatos, CA

Jul 2018 - Present

Sr Software Engineer - Compute Platform

- Building and maintaining the control plane for container platform at Netflix using mesos/kubernetes on Amazon EC2.
- Designed and built the titus job activity history service which showed the event history for a job(creation/modification aka scaling/deletion)
- Built a docker image metadata cache from the docker registry

Mesosphere, San Francisco, CA

Sept 2016 - Jul 2018

Software Developer, Cluster operations

- Worked on making container orchestration cluster upgrades seamless.
- Worked on building DC/OS(Mesos) services such as cluster and node checks and dcos licensing.

AMAZON WEB SERVICES, Cupertino, CA

Aug 2013 – Aug 2016

Software Developer, EC2

- o Added support for new linux kernels for the EC2 VM Import/Export service.
- Expand the service to newer regions and automate deployments.
- Lead the effort to reduce operations pain and focus on providing a better customer experience.

CISCO SYSTEMS INC, San Jose, CA

Jul 2010 - Aug 2013

Software Developer

• Worked on Catalyst 4500[®] 32 port switch linecards and VSS.

BITS NETWORKED SYSTEMS LABORATORY, Chicago, IL

May 2009 – May 2010

Research Assistant, University of Illinois at Chicago Mentor: Dr. Jacob Eriksson

Optimized long range wireless throughput by developing a new rate adaptation algorithm.

MOTOROLA, Schlaumburg, IL

May 2008 – Aug 2008

Summer Intern

o Implemented the AV standards version 3 for UPNP protocol, used for DLNA in set top boxes.

Education

University of Illinois at Chicago, Chicago, IL

Aug 2007 – May 2010

M. S. in Computer Science.

Master's Thesis: Asymmetry Aware Rate Adaptation (AARA) algorithm .

Advisor: Dr. Jacob Eriksson.

CBIT, Osmania University, Hyderabad, India

Aug 2003 – May 2007

Bachelor of Technology, Computer Science and Engineering.

Professional Activities

Volunteered with the organization of Amazon Women in Engineering for Grace Hopper Conference 2014.

Volunteered at March of dimes, Habitat for Humanity, and Turning wheels for kids.

References available upon request.